hey well good afternoon everybody
哎好，大家下午好
welcome good to see you and welcome to
欢迎很高兴 见到你，欢迎 到
our viewers on video as well okay so
我们 对视频 的观众 也 这么 好
today we're going to look at some
今天我们来看看一些
additional issues around the problem of
周围的人的问题， 其他 问题
synchronizing threaded programs first
第一同步线程程序
though let's review from last time a few
但让我们从最后 一次 审查 的 几个
of the concepts so recall that a
的概念， 所以记得，
semaphore is a non non- global
信号量是一个非全球非
synchronization variables manipulated by
同步变量通过操纵
DMV operations and the P operation takes
DMV操作和P操作需要
as an argument a semaphore if the
作为自变量的信号，如果
semaphore values non zero it decrements
旗语重视它递减非零
the semaphore and then continues if the
信号量，然后继续，如果
if the semaphore value is zero then it
如果信号量的值是 零，那么它
blocks waiting for that that semaphore
块等待这个信号量
value to be incremented by a V operation
值，以用V操作被递增
after the V operation increments after
在V操作增量之后后
some of the operation increments the
一些操作的递增
semaphore the P operation continues by
信号量P操作 的继续
decrementing asking and returning
问递减和返回
control to the caller the D operation
控制给调用者 D操作
never blocks it it first it increments
从来没有阻止它首先它 增加
the semaphore value s and then it looks
该信号值s，然后它看起来
in the queue of four to see if there's
在四个队列，看是否有
any processes that are blocked waiting
被阻止等待的任何过程
for that some before to be nonzero if
对于一些之前不为零 ，如果
there are then it selects one of those
有那么它选择其中的一个
using some unspecified criteria and then
使用一些未指定的条件，然后
it restarts that it restarts that thread
它重新启动，它重新启动该线程
that's or that P operation that's
这或者就是这样P动作
waiting waiting on the semaphore okay
在信号好的等待等待
and then this the semantics of the the P
然后对P的这种语义
and V ensure that semaphore values are
和V确保信号的值是
always greater than equal to zero now
总是大于等于 现在 为零
the first thing we saw how to protect
的第一件事，我们看到了如何 保护
shared variables by by using a semaphore
通过使用信号量的共享变量
called the mutex that guarantees
所谓，保证互斥
mutually exclusive access to the
互斥访问
critical sections that are updating that
这要更新的关键部分
those variables or data structures and
这些变量或数据结构和
and the way that we do this is very
而我们这样做的方法 是非常
simple we initialize the mutex to one
简单，我们初始化 互斥锁到一个
and then surround the critical section
然后围绕关键部分
with a P and a V now there's a there's
用P以及V 现在有一个 有
other ways that we can so here here's an
其他方面，我们可以因此 在这里这里是一个
example where we're using semaphore is
例如我们使用旗语 在哪里
to provide mutual exclusion but we can
提供相互排斥，但我们可以
also use some of our semaphores to
还使用 我们的 某些 信号量来
coordinate access to shared data
坐标访问共享数据
structures in different ways and so the
结构以不同的方式等等
idea here before we were using that the
这里的想法，我们使用的是前
semaphore just to protect the access to
信号只是为了保护访问
a shared variable but we can also
共享变量，但我们也可以
coordinate access in different ways by
协调不同的方式获得通过
keeping and this in this in these in
保持和这本在这些中
these kind of scenarios we're using the
这些类型的场景中，我们使用了
semaphore to keep track of State to
信号量来跟踪国家 来
count to count things to keep track of
数数的东西来跟踪
State and to notify other other threads
州和通知 等其他线程
of changes in state okay so it's a very
在状态 好的变化， 所以这是一个非常
different usage model and two classic
不同的使用模式和两个经典
examples that we're going to look at are
我们要去的例子 来看看是
the producer consumer problem and the
生产者 消费者问题和
readers writers problem so let's look at
读者的作家的问题，所以让我们来看看
producer consumer first so the idea in
生产者消费者 首次如此的想法
the producer consumer problem is that
生产者消费者的问题是，
you have a shared resource in the form
你必须 在形式 的共享资源
of a buffer the buffer has a bounded
一个缓冲器 的缓冲器 已经有界
size so it consists of n slots and each
大小，以便它是由n个时隙，并且每个的
slot can hold an item okay the there's a
槽可容纳一个项目没关系的有一个
producer thread which produces items and
生产者线程产生的项目和
then inserts them into the buffer and
然后将它们插入到缓冲区和
there's a consumer thread that retrieves
有检索消费者线程
removes items from the buffer and then
将删除缓冲器中，然后项
consumes them by acting on them and so
通过对他们采取行动，因此他们消费
processing on them in some way so the
以某种方式让他们处理
the synchronization variable the
同步变量
synchronization pattern is that the
同步模式是该
producer waits for an empty slot right
生产者等待空 插槽右
so if there's if the buffer is full the
所以如果有如果缓冲区已满
producer can't insert an item into the
生产者不能插入一个项目到
buffer so it waits for an empty slot and
缓冲所以它等待一个空时隙和
then when it finds an empty slot when an
然后当它发现当一个空槽
empty slot becomes available it inserts
空槽变得可用 它插入
the item into the buffer and then it
该项目入 缓冲区 ，然后
notifies the consumer that there's now a
通知有现在的消费者
new item in the in the in the buffer the
在新 项目 的缓冲
consumer of course that has to wait for
当然，消费者有等待
an item to show up in the buffer
一个项目出现在缓冲区
otherwise I mean it can't remove an item
否则我的意思是不能删除的项
from an empty buffer so it has to wait
从空的缓冲区，所以它必须等待
for for an item to be available in the
对于一个 项目是在现有的
buffer and when an item becomes
缓冲器和当物品变得
available it removes it from the buffer
它可从缓冲区中删除
and then notifies the the producer that
并通知生产者是
there's now an available slot okay so
现在有一个可用插槽好了，
this actually this very simple pattern
这其实这个非常简单的模式
is actually really really useful and
其实真的有用 ，
shows up in a lot of applications so for
在大量 的 应用程序，以便 为显示出来
example a multimedia application in a
例如，在多媒体应用
multimedia application the producer
多媒体应用制片人
might be producing say MPEG MPEG frames
可能会产生MPEG说帧MPEG
in it in a video and the consumer would
它在视频 和消费者会
be consuming those those MPEG frames and
被消耗那些那些MPEG帧和
then painting the screen appropriately
然后适当地画屏幕
another important application is in
另一个重要的应用是在
graphical user interfaces so graphical
图形用户接口，以便图形化
user interfaces are typically
用户接口通常
implemented using this producer-consumer
使用这种 生产者-消费者实现
model where the mouse clicks motions and
模型，其中，鼠标点击动作和
the in the of the mouse keyboard clicks
中鼠标键盘点击
those are all recorded as events they're
这些都被记录为他们的活动
detected by the system recorded as
通过记录为系统检测
events and placed into a some kind of a
事件并放入某种形式的
queue and then various other parts of
排队和然后各种其它部件
the system retrieve items from the queue
该系统从队列中检索项
and and react to them so for example the
和， 并将它们反应，从而例如
graphic system will retrieve events like
图形系统将检索类似事件
Mouse events
鼠标事件
and mouse movements mouse clicks and it
和鼠标移动鼠标点击它
will paint the screen accordingly right
会画画屏幕右侧相应的
a little it'll it'll reflect it will
一点点，它会，它会体现它会
repaint the screen so that the to show
重绘屏幕， 使显示
you that the cursor is moving right or
您将光标移动向右或
if you change the focus it'll it'll
如果你改变了焦点，它会，它会
repaint it so it's a very very common
重绘它，所以它是一个非常非常普遍
model and as we'll see later
建模和以后我们会看到
multi-threaded we can build
多线程的，我们可以建立
multi-threaded concurrent servers using
使用多线程并发服务器
this this model so let's see how we
这这种模式让我们看看我们如何
would implement producer/consumer on an
将实施上的生产者/消费者
n-element buffer so this the
正元件缓冲器所以这将
implementation requires the mutex to
实现需要互斥
Garrety mutually exclusive access to the
Garrety 互斥访问
resource of course and then it requires
当然，资源，然后它需要
then two other semaphores counting
然后另外两个信号计数
semaphores slots is a semaphore that
信号量是时隙一信号量
counts the available slots in the buffer
计算在缓冲区中的可用插槽
an item is count to the available items
一个项目算到可用项目
okay
好的
and we've can implement it with this
我们已经可以用这个实现它
this package called s bus so ESPA the s
这个软件包叫做 s的总线所以ESPA的S
buff package defines a type called s
抛光轮包定义类型 称为S
buff underscore t that packages up all
浅黄色下划线牛逼的是封装了所有
of the data structures that are needed
是 需要 的数据结构的
to implement the shared buffer so
实现共享缓冲器 ，以便
there's a pointer to the the buffer
有一个指向缓冲区
which we were going to implement as an
这是我们将要实现作为
array and and we'll implement our
阵列，我们将实现我们的
circular buffer on this array the
这个阵列上循环缓冲区的
maximum number of slots and so the size
时隙的最大数目 等的大小
of the buffer and then two pointers
缓冲器然后 两个指针 和
front and rear to keep track of the the
前后跟踪 的中
front and rear of the of the buffer so
前部和后部的缓冲器，以便
to keep track of the first and last
跟踪的第一个和 最后的
items in the buffer and then the three
在缓冲区的项目，然后三
semaphores the mutex and in the two
信号灯互斥锁，并在两
counting semaphores and then the package
计数信号，然后将包
consists of these four public functions
由这四个公共 职能
s bus a knit which creates the is called
s 的总线 它创建了被称为针织
once to create the buffer and initialize
一旦创建缓冲区 并初始化
everything allocate the space and
一切分配 空间，
initialize things and then d in it which
初始化的东西，那么d在它其中
which frees up the space and then
这可释放一些空间，然后
a function to insert an item into the
一个函数来插入 项目 进入
queue and a function to remove an item
排队和一个函数来 删除项目
from a queue and return that item so in
从队列中，并返回该项目因此在
this case items are just
这种情况下，项目仅仅是
so to create the to initialize the this
所以创建初始化这个
buffer with n slots we first allocate
与n个时隙，我们首先分配缓冲器
the space for the buffer and MN we set
为缓冲区和MN 我们设置的空间
the we set the size to be the value and
在我们设置的大小为 价值和
that was passed in we indicate the empty
这是通过在我们表明空
buffer by setting front-and-rear to be 0
通过设置前-后缓冲器为 0
okay and so whenever front and rear are
很好，而且所以每当前部和后部是
0 that's we have an empty buffer and
0这就是我们有一个空的缓冲区和
then we initialize the 3 semaphore so
然后我们初始化3 信号灯等等
the mutex like all meu Texas is
像所有 MEU 得克萨斯州的互斥
initialized to 1 the slot semaphore
初始化为1 槽旗语
which keeps track of the number of
其跟踪的 数量
available slots is initialized to N and
可用时隙被初始化为N和
the item semaphore is initialized to 0
该项目旗语初始化为0
ok and D in that is really simple it
确定 和D 是 非常简单的它
just frees up the the heap space that we
刚刚解放了的堆空间，我们
allocated ok so now let's look at how we
确定分配所以现在 让我们来看看我们如何
insert an item into the buffer so we
插入项目到缓冲区 ，所以我们
call we want to insert this integer item
叫我们要插入此整数项目
into this buffer pointed at by SP so
到此缓冲区指向由SP所以
first the thread waits for an available
第一线程等待可用
slot ok by doing a P on the slot
插槽通过 在槽 做在 P OK
semaphore right so P will block until
旗语权利，使P将阻塞，直到
slots is greater than or equal to 1 okay
槽是大于或等于 1 行
once there's an available slot then it
一旦有 可用的插槽 则
it then it's going to it's going to
它然后它 会 它会
update the rear of the of the buffer ok
更新的后部的缓冲器的 行
so we're going to put this item on to
所以我们打算把这个项目上
the rear of the buffer and so it needs
缓冲器的后部，并因此需要
to protect that access to that shared
以保护访问该共享
buffer with the mutex then it does the
与互斥缓冲区，它的
bike bike by doing a pee on the mutex
通过互斥做撒尿自行车自行车
updating updating our rear pointer okay
更新更新我们的后指针好吗
so we pre incremented so we increment
所以我们前期增加，所以我们增加
the rear pointer and then take take the
后指针再 取取
mod of that n/2
的是n / 2模
to compute the index that we're going to
来计算， 我们要去指数
insert the item into okay then we do a V
插入的项目 进入好吧，那么我们做的为V
on the mutex okay so that other other
互斥好让其他其他
threads can can update that that shared
线程可以可以更新该共享
data structure and then we do a V on the
数据结构，然后我们做一个V来
number of items to notify any consumers
项目的数量，以通知所有消费者
that there's now an item in the in the
现在有一个项目在中
buffer so this this V is kind of
缓冲所以这此V是一种
interesting you think it's kind of like
有趣的你觉得它有点 像
a signal right so you're sort of
信号右所以你之类的
signaling consumers that now some of
信令 消费者，现在 一些
that has occurred in the system now to
现在已经发生系统
remove an item it's it's symmetric but
删除它是对称的项目，但
instead of instead of operating on the
代替的 ，而不是 在操作
slots that before it operates on the
它在运行之前插槽
items semaphore so to remove an item a
项目信号量所以要删除的 项
consumer first does a P on the items
消费者首先做的项目为P
semaphore so this now is waiting for an
旗语所以这个现在 正在等待
available item it's waiting for the
它等待可用项目
semaphore to be greater than equal to
信号量为大于 等于 大于
one when that happens then the P the P
一个当这种情况发生则在P在P
returns and then we do we do the update
返回，然后我们所做 的更新
protected by a mutex by pre-incrementing
通过一个互斥体 通过预递增 保护
front taking the mod n and then reading
前服用MOD n和然后读
that value and returning it and placing
该值并将其返回，并把
it into this local local variable item
它进入这个地方局部变量项目
then we release the mutex and then we do
那么我们释放 互斥锁 ，然后我们做
a V on the number of slots which which
上的 槽 数为V，其其
is an announcement to the to any
是公告的 任何
producers that there's now a new
生产者有现在是一个新的
available slot okay
可用插槽好吗
any questions about that so it's a
有关的任何问题所以这是一个
little more subtle
小 更微妙
this looks really simple but like all
这看起来很简单，但像所有的
concurrency problems it's actually very
并发性问题，它实际上很
subtle so you can have potential you can
微妙的所以你可以有 潜力，你 可以
have many producers and many many
有许多生产者和很多很多
consumers all operating on the same you
消费者都在同一您在操作
know the same the same shared buffer so
知道 相同的相同的共享的缓冲器，以便
this so what would happen if if we had
这所以会发生什么，如果如果我们有
to two consumers did a Appy on this item
两个消费者 做了APPY关于 这个项目
semaphore at the exact same time say
信号在准确的同时说
we're running on two cores and and we
我们的两个核心，并和我们运行
have two threads and they each each
有两个线程，它们分别各
execute that P at the same time on that
执行将P在同一时间上
that same that same item semaphore okay
相同的是同一个项目 旗语好吗
so even even though they access it at
因此，即使即使他们访问的
the same time the kernel will make sure
同时 内核将确保
that one of them will execute first okay
其中一人 将执行第一好吗
so the kernel will serialize those P
所以内核将系列化的P
operations and if there's no telling
操作如果有难以预料
which one gets it first but whoever acts
哪一个首先得到它，但谁的行为
whoever runs there P first will will
谁运行有P首先意愿会
decrement this this item semaphore and
这个递减这个项目 和 信号灯
then when the next when the next thread
那么下 一次 ，当一个线程
executes it's P items will either be
执行它是P＆的项目将是
zero or nonzero okay as a result so
零 或非零 行作为结果，以便
somebody wins there's kind of a ton of
有人赢有 那种一吨的
like a controlled race and somebody wins
喜欢控制比赛，有人赢
the race always wins the race because
比赛总是赢得比赛，因为
the kernel is serializing these P
内核被序列化 这些P
operations and it's executing them
操作和它的执行它们
atomically okay
原子好吗
okay now the the there's a
还好现在的有一个
generalization of the mutual exclusion
互斥的泛化
problem called the reader writer problem
问题称为 读写器问题
so with with the mutual mutual exclusion
所以与相互 互斥
problem we were guaranteeing each thread
问题我们保证每个线程
mutually exclusive access to to its
互斥访问其
critical section that's updating a
关键的部分，其真实更新
particular resource or accessing a
特定资源或访问
particular resource and we did this the
特别是资源 ，我们这样做的
exact same way whether that access was a
完全相同的方式访问是否是一个
read or write okay but that's that's
读或写的不错，但就是这样的
overly conservative in this case because
在这种情况下，因为过于保守
we could if all we were doing if we had
我们可以在所有我们正在做 ，如果我们 有
multiple threads that were just reading
多线程只是读书
the resource there would be no reason to
资源就没有理由
do P's and DS on that resource or if
做普的和DS上的资源，或者
we're not changing if we're not changing
如果我们不改变我们不会改变
the resource we're just reading it and
资源我们只是读 它，
there's nobody else writing it then then
有没有人 写它，然后再
there's no need to protect write so it
有没有需要 保护写这么多吧
for readers we can have as many readers
读者，我们可以有很多的读者
as we want all at the same time reading
因为我们希望所有在同一时间阅读
reading the the resource the variable or
阅读资源的变量或
set of variables and there's no need for
设置的变量，而且也没有必要
any kind of synchronization at all okay
任何一种同步的 所有好吗
so the producer consumer is sort of a
所以生产者 消费者排序的
generalization of that mutual exclusion
该互斥的泛化
problem which enforces mutual exclusion
问题这就加强相互排斥
only when it's absolutely necessary okay
只有当它是绝对必要 没关系
so there can be is there there can be as
所以不可能有是有可能，因为
many readers reading the resource but
许多读者阅读 资源，但
when a writer wants to write then it it
当一个作家要写那么它
has to have mutual exclusive access to
必须有互斥访问
the resource okay
资源好吗
so this is the kind of thing this is
所以这是什么样的事情，这 是
also a very useful pattern you have in
也是一个非常 有用的模式，你必须在
an online airline reservation system you
网上机票预订系统，您
have multiple clients accessing a shared
有多个客户端访问 共享
database okay so as long as those
数据库好了，所以只要 这些
clients are reading the database you can
客户正在阅读的数据库，你可以
have they can all be reading at the same
他们都可以在 同一 被阅读
time but as soon as somebody wants to
时间，但只要有人想
make a reservation and update the
预约和更新
database then that update has to happen
数据库那么更新有发生
mutually exclusive way you know if you
相互排斥的方式，你知道，如果你
had also if you had like any kind of
也如果你有一个像任何形式的
shared data structure like a cache in a
共享数据结构像在高速缓存
in a concurrent proxy like that you're
在这样的你是一个并发代理
going to be writing soon or if you
马上就会或者如果你写
haven't already started that cache is
尚未 启动该缓存是
being shared by multiple threads and
由多个线程所共享和
multiple threads may be reading that
多个线程可以读取
cache but when something when you when
缓存但是当东西时，你的时候
you get a new page and you want to cache
你会得到一个新的页面，并要缓存
it then that that that constitutes a
它那么该 构成一个
right and that right needs to happen in
权，这一权利需要发生在
a mutually exclusive way now the initial
现在是相互排斥的方式初始
research the researchers that that posed
研究认为是造成科研人员
this readers writers problems in define
在定义这个读者的作家的问题
sort of several classes of reader writer
排序几类读写器的
problems the first reader writer readers
问题的第一读写器 读取器
writers problems is an implementation
作家的问题是一个实现
that favors readers right so the idea is
有 利于读者权这样的 想法是
that no reader should be kept waiting
没有 读者应保持等待
right unless an a writer already has a P
右除非作家已经具有P
as has sort of acquired the lock on that
作为具有某种获取了该锁
of the mutex on that on that resource so
对互斥量上 的 资源，以便
in this case you know say there's a
在这种情况下，你知道说有一个
writer waiting to get to acquire the
作家等着去收购
mutex and another reader comes in then
互斥和其他读者进来然后
in this implementation that reader would
在此实现， 读者会
get priority over the writer and it
得到优先于 作家和其
would be able to to read the to at to do
将能够读取 在做
its read and the writer would have to
它的读取和作家将不得不
wait and so a court now if multiple
等待等法院 ，现在如果多
readers keep coming in then this could
读者不断在那么这可能来临
starve out the writer right
饿死了作家的权利
so a writer could be starved sort of
所以一个作家可能被饿死的排序
indefinitely waiting for all these
无限期地等待所有这些
readers to finish and it's just based on
读者来完成，它只是基于
you know based based on how the
你知道基于如何基于
operating system decides to schedule
操作系统决定安排
these these various reader reader
这些这些不同的读者阅读器
threads the the writer could be could be
线程作家可能是可能是
starved out so that's what that's what
饿死了所以这就是 那是什么
we mean by when we say that it's a
我们的意思是，当我们说这是 一个
Drewes readers now the second readers
德鲁斯读者现在 第二个读者
various problem is the sort of the the
各种问题的排序 中 的
opposite of that so it favors writers
那相反的，因此有利于作家
right so any once a writer is ready to
右所以一旦任何一个作家准备
to write then it gets priority over any
写那么它在任何获得优先权
waiting readers so in in this case if we
等待读者所以在这种情况下，如果我们
have if we have multiple writers that
有，如果我们有多个 作家说
want to write they could starve out
想写他们可能饿死了
readers now there's there's other
读者现在有有其他
variants that sort of deal with this
变种那种交易与 此
starvation issue this potential
饥饿问题这一潜力
starvation issue but we won't look at
饥饿问题，但我们不会看
them here so the let's look at the
他们在这里所以让我们看看
solution to the first readers writers
解决第一个作家的读者
problem so write initially a thread is
问题这么写的 最初一个线程
either a reader in this sort of
无论是在这种阅读器
simplification or it's a writer if we
简化或者 它是一个作家，如果我们
look at the writers this is pretty
看看作家，这是非常
simple it's just the writers are just
简单， 它只是 作家只是
doing a peon this semaphore so this this
做日工此信号灯所以这本
the semaphore W is the sort of serves as
信号灯W是那种充当的
like a mutex that protects the resource
像保护资源互斥
for writers so it ensures that there's
作家所以它可以确保有
at most one writer at any time executing
至多在 任何 时候 一个作家 执行
its critical section and it does that by
它的关键部分， 它通过
just this this variation this familiar P
只是这此变化这个熟悉的P
followed follows I of V can read errs
其次如下 -v可以阅读ERRS 的我
are a little more interesting so with
有一点更有趣 所以用
with the reader we have the shared this
与读者，我们共享这
global variable called read count which
所谓阅读数全局变量
is going to keep track of the number of
是要保持 数量的轨道
readers that are waiting to to read the
正在等待 阅读的读者
to read the resource and there's a mutex
阅读资源，有一个互斥体
semaphore mutex that protect protects
信号灯互斥保护保护
the accesses the
在访问
updates to read count okay the reads and
更新阅读次数没关系的读取和
the rights to up to read count and then
权念计数，然后
there's this w semaphore which as we saw
有这正如 我们所看到 该 W信号
here is used to protect the critical
这里是用来保护的关键
section in the writer and initially both
在作家和最初两部分
of these are set to one so the reader in
这些被设置为一个，这样读者
this infinite loop in each iteration of
在每次迭代这个无限循环
this infinite loop it is going to
这个无限循环 它会
increment read count so it protects that
增量读计数，因此可保护
that access by by doing a P on the new
该访问由上新 做的为 P
text which is associated with recount so
这与验票 关联 ，以便文本
only one only one reader can can be so
只有一个只有一个 读者可以可以 如此
this this region between the P and the V
在P 和 V 之间的这个区域
constitutes the critical section
构成临界区
corresponding to read count so after the
相应的阅读数量，使得后
P completes then it then we increment
P完成再然后我们增加
the read count so now there's an
读计数所以现在有一个
additional reader and so we can have
额外的读卡器等 ，我们可以有
potentially arbitrary number of these
的这些可能是任意数量的
reader threads right so this we're
读者线程右所以这个我们
indicating that there's there's there's
这表明有有有
a new reader now and if read count is
新的读者现在，如果读计数
one that that means we're the first
一说，这意味着我们是第一个
reader okay so this is sort of the first
读者好了，所以这是排序第一的
reader into the this implicit queue of
读者带入的这种隐性的队列
waiting readers so if read count is one
等待的读者，所以如果读计数为1
if we're the first reader then we do a P
如果我们是第一个读者，然后我们做在P
on W okay which now will lock out any
W 上 还好现在将 锁定 任何
any any future writers now if there's
任何现在任何未来的作家，如果有
already a writer that's done it's P of W
已经这样做了 它一个作家的w ^ p个
then this will block waiting for that
那么 这将 阻止等待 那
writer to finish okay but if there's no
作家完成 不错，但如果没有
writer in inside of its critical
作家在其关键的内部
critical section then this P will just
临界区那么这个P将只
decrement the semaphore W from 1 to 0
减小信号W的1到0
and then lock out any subsequent writers
然后锁定任何 后续的作家
okay after so now after it's done this
还好所以现在经过后，它的完成这个
increment and read of the read count
增量 和读取计数的阅读
variable then it releases the mutex so
然后变量，它释放的互斥体 ，
that other readers can can access
其他读者可以可以访问
recount
叙事
okay now but it's still holding it's
现在没事了，但它仍然保持它的
it's it's it's holding so this is this
这是它的控股，所以这是这个
is kind of interesting right it's it's
是一种有趣的 右侧是它的
it's holding the semaphore that that
它所持有的信号量 即
locks out the writers but it's not
锁住了作家，但它不是
holding the any-any mutex right so the
持有任何-任何互斥的权利，因此
reader now can just can just read it can
读者现在可以只可刚 读它可以
do its read and other readers that are
做 它的读取和其他 读者是
in the same the same section of the code
在码的 同一相同 部
can also do their reads right so so
还可以做他们的阅读权，从而使
we're not so we're allowing multiple
我们没有，所以我们要允许多个
readers now inside this critical section
现在的读者这个临界区内
but but no writers okay so everything so
但是却没有作家好了，一切都那么
everything works looks like it works
一切工作看起来像它的工作原理
good now after after we read now the
现在好后之后，我们现在读
number of readers now is going to be we
读者的数量，现在将是 我们
want to decrement the number of readers
要递减读者的数量
so we acquire the mutex on on read count
所以我们获得互斥体上读取数
we decrement read count and then we
我们读递减计数，然后我们
check to see if we're the last reader
检查，看看是否是最后的读者
okay so if there's no more readers in
好了，如果没有更多的 读者
other words if read count is zero then
换句话说，如果读计数为零，则
with now we can release the mutex for
与现在我们可以释放互斥
the writer so that any now writers can
笔者让任何现在的作家能
can access that resource and after we
可以访问该资源后，我们
release that the writers of the writers
释放作家的作家
mutex then we release the mutex for read
互斥然后我们释放读互斥
count
计数
so many questions about about this so an
关于这个如此的这么多问题
interesting for you to think about just
有趣的你想想刚
you have any spare time is how you might
您有任何空闲时间你是怎么可能
how you might write a version of this
你会如何写一个版本，这
readers writers problem that favors
读者的作家的问题，有利于
writers instead of readers yes oh no
作者而非读者是没有哦
okay so the question is a mutex allows
好了 ，所以这个问题 是 一个互斥量允许
for multiple readers the fact that we
多读者的事实，我们
know the fact that we're releasing this
知道我们将要发布 这样 一个事实
mutex here that this mutex is only only
互斥这里，这个互斥量也仅仅是
protecting access to read count so we
保护访问读取次数 ，所以我们
acquire it here and we release it here
在这里获取它，我们在这里释放
after we've after we've accessed read
我们已经经过后，我们访问过读
count okay but we're not protecting the
算不错，但我们还没有 保护
critical section of the reader with any
与任何读取器的关键部分
with any mutex except for we're we're
与除了我们我们是任何互斥
keeping writers out by if we're the
保持了作家通过，如果我们的
first one in if we're the first reader
第一个在如果我们是第 一个读者
you can add just like this implicit
您可以添加 就这样隐
queue of readers that we're keeping
读者的队列 我们保持
track of with read count okay so if
轨道与读算 好了，所以如果
we're the first ones in meaning we're
我们是第一个出来的意思我们
the first reader then we we acquire this
第一读者，然后我们我们获得了这个
the p on the writers mutex now if
现在如果在作家互斥在p
there's of course if there's a writer
有，当然，如果有一个作家
inside this critical section then this P
这里面关键部分则该p
will wait until the writer releases okay
会等到作家释放好吗
but once once we've acquired this this
但一旦一旦我们获得的这本
this mutex W then we're block we're
这种互斥W，则我们是 块我们
locking out any writers okay because
锁定任何作家没关系，因为
they'll any writer that that arrives
他们会任何笔者，到达
we'll do a P and it will block right
我们会做一个P和它会阻止权
here on waiting for that W to be nonzero
在这里 等待的w 为 非零
okay so so we're just we're blocking out
好了，所以我们只是在我们阻挡在外
any writers but then we're allowing any
任何作家，但随后我们 允许任何
readers to just to access the resource
读者只需访问该资源
okay okay good
还好还好好
yes question question is blocking slow
是问题的问题是阻止慢
it can be depends well first of all
它可以 很好 取决于 首先的
you're making a call into the kernel so
你正在做一个进入 内核的 调用 等等
it's a system call so you're crossing
这是一个系统调用，所以你穿越
that boundary and there's always
该边界和总有
overhead associated with that and then
开销与该再关联
blocking you're blocked until you know
堵你封锁，直到你知道
it can be sort of an arbitrary amount of
它可以是排序 的 任意 量 的
time right until someone doesn't some
正确的时间，直到有人没有一些
thread does a V so yeah it can't be slow
螺纹确实为V 所以是不能慢
right it just it just depends you can't
右它只是它只是取决于你不能
it's really hard to bound the time that
这真的很难约束时间
you're going to be blocked now if you
你要现在如果你被封锁
write the program correctly eventually
写程序最终正确
you'll be unblocked you know eventually
你会被解封你 最终 知道
some thread will execute a V but when
一些线程将执行为V，但是当
we're sort of assuming that the kernel
我们那种假设 内核
does some kind of when it implements its
做某种它实现的时候了
V it does some kind of fair scheduling
v更高的IT做某种 公平调度
that so I blocked a block P won't be in
该所以阻止的块P不会在
its queue for forever right that the
它永远正确的队列
kernel does some kind of something
内核做某种东西
that's fair so it did guarantees that a
这是公平的，因此没有保证一个
P won't remain blocked indefinitely
P将不会无限期封锁
any other questions okay so we can kind
还好 有任何问题 ，所以我们可以种
of put all of this together and and use
的把所有的这一起 ，和使用
the use our producer-consumer model to
在使用我们的生产者-消费者模式
implement a pre threaded concurrent echo
实现预线程并发 回波
server now so far when we when we've
服务器现在为止，当我们的时候，我们已经
used threads to in all our examples of
使用的线程在所有我们 的例子
using threads and processes for servers
使用线程和 进程的 服务器
we created a new thread or process
我们创建了一个新的线程或进程
whenever a new connection request
每当一个新的连接 请求
arrived and then when when and then that
赶到，那么当时，然后是
that thread interacted with the client
该线程交互与客户端
and then whenever whenever that
然后每当每当
interaction was finished it closed the
互动结束它关闭
connection and exited and killed the
连接和退出，杀死了
thread or process now that's that's okay
线程或进程，现在这 没关系
but it's it's inefficient because we're
但它是 低效的，因为我们是
this creating and killing threads
这个创建和杀死线程
introduces overhead so a another way to
引入架空所以另一种方式
do this is to pretreat the threads or
这样做是为了预处理线或
processes ahead of time create a pool of
流程提前创建池
threads where each thread so we create a
线程，每个线程，所以我们创建一个
pool of these worker threads where each
这些工作线程池，每个
of these water threads interacts with
这些水的线程与互动
can interact with a client okay so
可以与客户端交互好了，
instead of sort of creating processes
而不是那种创造过程
and threads on on-demand we create a
和线程在 点播我们创建了一个
what we call a set of pre threaded or
我们所说的一组预先螺纹或
pre threaded threads or pre forked
预螺纹螺纹或预分叉
processes that do the work so the idea
该做的工作这样的想法流程
is that we have this master thread in
就是我们在这个主线程
our server that's waiting for connection
我们是在等待连接服务器
requests from clients by repeated calls
重复调用来自客户端的请求
to accept and then when it when this
接受，然后当它时，这
thread receives the connection request
线程接收该连接请求
from the client the accept the accept
从客户端 接受接受
call the accept function returns the
调用accept函数返回
connected file descriptor ok associated
连接文件描述符确定相关联的
with the connection to the client and
与连接到客户端，
then it inserts that descriptor into a
然后它插入该描述符到一个
into a buffer ok now remember
到缓冲区中确定现在 还记得
descriptors are just small integers that
描述都只是小整数那
index the descriptor table and so they
指标描述符表，所以他们
can be passed around
可以传递
from thread to thread because all the
从线程线程，因为所有的
threads are sharing the same the same
线程共享相同的同
set that same descriptor table right so
设置相同的描述符表这样的权利
the master thread puts the repeatedly
主线程把反复
accepts connection requests and inserts
接受连接请求和插入
the corresponding connected file
相应的连接文件
descriptor into the buffer now each
描述符入缓冲区现在每
worker thread waits for the so in this
工作线程在此等待如此
case the items are descriptors so the
区分的项目描述符所以
worker threads they're all waiting on
工作线程，他们都在等待
this for items to appear in this buffer
本项 出现在这个缓冲区
okay and when an item appears one of the
好吧，当一个项目出现的一个
threads will remove that item and then
线程将删除的项目，然后
use that descriptor to interact with the
使用该描述与互动
with the client over the connected file
与客户端在连接文件
descriptor associated with the
描述与关联
connection that exists between the
该之间存在连接
client and the server okay so now we
客户端， 因此现在的服务器 还好我们
have we have the concurrency comes in
有，我们有并发进来
the form of these multiple worker
这些多个工作形式
threads interacting with with multiple
线程与多互动
clients and then when a worker thread
客户端，然后当工人线程
finishes servicing a particular client
完成服务于特定的客户端
then it just goes and it checks for the
那么它 只是 和 它检查
next file descriptor in the buffer okay
在缓冲区未来文件描述符好吗
so this is much more efficient than our
所以这是远远超过我们的效率
previous model where for each new client
以前的模型， 其中为每个新客户
we had to create a thread or a process
我们必须创建一个线程或 进程
and then destroy that thread or process
然后销毁线程或进程
once we were finished
一旦我们 完成 了
okay so we're sort of re-advertise that
好了，所以我们要排序的重新通告
we had to go through to create these
我们不得不去通过创建 这些
worker threads by leaving them running
工作线程通过让他们运行
and then replacing the destruction or
然后更换破坏或
the killing of that thread with
该线程 的杀灭与
replacing it with just a simple as
只是一个简单的替换它
simple and very fast operation of
简单 ， 非常快的操作
removing an item from the buffer okay
在从缓冲器取出的项目行
okay so let's see how we would we would
好了，让我们看看会怎样，我们会
implement this and like like all of
实现这个，喜欢像所有的
these server examples it's surprisingly
这些服务器的例子是出奇
simple right this is a fully functioning
简单的权利，这是一个全功能的
a real server but we can do it in one
一个真正的服务器，但我们可以在一个做到这一点
one page one page of code so for this
一个页面的代码在一个页面所以 这
preet we're going to use threads for our
普里特我们将使用线程 我们
concurrent server and we're going to use
并发服务器，我们要使用
the s buff package so we're going to
在S BUFF包，所以我们打算
create this this shared buffer global
创建这个这个共享缓冲区全球
variable called s buff and we have a
变量称为S的buff，我们有 一个
listening descriptor and connected
听描述符和连接
descriptor and we have the client length
描述和我们有客户端长度
and client adder that will be used in
将在使用和客户端加法器
the accept call and we have the thread
在接受电话，我们有螺纹
ID that will be used in the when we
将在何时被使用 ID 我们
create that when we create this thread
创建当我们创建这个线程
so now that we start by we're going to
所以现在我们通过我们将开始
in this program we're going to pass in
在这个方案我们打算在传递
the port number so the server is going
所以服务器的端口号是怎么回事
to be listening on some port so we
被一些端口 ，所以我们 在听
passed that port number in as the first
在作为第一通过了端口号
argument so we call open listened FD on
参数 ，所以我们称之为开放式听取 FD上
our V of one an open listen FD creates a
我们一个一个开放第五听 FD创建
listening descriptor and returns it
听了描述，并返回
returns the value of that descriptor and
返回描述符的价值 ，
listen FD and then we call s buffin it
听FD然后我们称S buffin它
to to initialize our shared buffer with
以初始化我们共同的缓冲带
with s buff sized file descriptors and
与S 的buff 大小文件描述符 和
then we create a collection of n threads
然后我们创建N个线程的集合
worker threads on each of which will
对每一个工作线程会
execute the the thread routine which
执行线程例程
we've called thread and no argument so
当我们调用线程并没有这样的说法
once we create these all of these
一旦我们创建这些所有的这些
threads then we go in this infinite loop
线程然后我们去在这个无限循环
where we call accept
在这里我们调用 accept
on this listening descriptor so on that
在此聆听量，使得上
acceptable block until a connection
上可接受的 块直到 一连接
request arrives and when it does the
请求到达时，它的
accept returns with a connected file
接受与连接的文件返回
descriptor that can be used to to
描述符，可用于向
interact with the client and once we get
与 客户互动，一旦我们得到
that connected file descriptor then we
该连接的文件描述符那么我们
just that simply insert it we insert
只是简单地将其插入我们插入
that that connected file descriptor into
该所连接的文件描述符成
our shared buffer and then wait for the
我们共同的缓冲区，然后 等待
connection request the next connection
连接请求下一个连接
request so our servers very efficient
请求，以便我们的服务器非常有效
right we're just doing an accept and
正确的，我们只是在做 一个接受和
then a very fast insert into the buffer
然后非常快的 插入缓冲
okay and then we're going to let the
好吧 ，然后我们将 让
worker threads do all the work
工作线程做的所有工作
associated with those with that with
与那些具有 关联
with that that queue of descriptors now
与现在的描述符该队列
the thread routine first detaches okay
线程程序首先分离好吗
so this is a case where we don't want to
所以，这是我们不希望的情况下，
run joinable because we're never going
运行可连接的，因为我们永远不会
to to join we're never going to wait for
要加入我们永远不会 等待
these threads or have any any reason to
这些线程或有任何任何理由
kill them from the main thread so this
从主线程所以这次杀了他们
so now this worker thread and in this
所以现在这个工作线程，并在此
infinite loop each iteration it removes
无限循环每次迭代它消除
an item from the buffer so it blocks
从缓冲器中的项目，因此块
until there's an item that it can code
直到有一个项目，它可以编码
that it can remove from the buffer and
它可以从缓冲器中删除，并
it sets it to this local variable con ft
将其设置到这个局部变量CON英尺
and then it calls a helper sort of this
然后调用一个辅助类的这
this is like the helper function that
这就像 辅助函数
implements the logic for this this
实现逻辑该这
particular server and this is this in
特定的服务器，这是这
this case it's an echo server so this
这种情况下，它的回声服务器，因此这
this echo count routine will interact
这种回声计数程序将互动
with the client echoing whatever the
与客户端 呼应无论
client sends us until the client closes
客户端发送我们，直到客户机关闭
the connection and then when it so
该连接，然后当它这样
whenever the client is finished then
每当 客户端已经完成，然后
then we close the we close the our end
然后我们关闭我们关闭我们的最终
of the connection and go back and get
连接 和回去拿
the next item out of the buffer
下一个项目移出缓冲区
and I should point out that echo count
我要指出的是回声计数
is just a placeholder this could be
只是一个占位符，这可能是
anything this could be the logic for a
任何事情，这可能是一个逻辑
web server for any kind of web service
对于任何一种Web服务的 Web服务器
or any kind of service now the to
或任何种类的服务现在到
initialize this echo count function we
初始化这个回波计数功能我们
need to we need to initialize the mutex
需要我们需要 初始化 互斥锁
so we're so this echo count function is
所以我们所以这个回声计数功能
going to have it has a defines a global
要 拥有它有一个定义一个全局
variable called byte count so this in
变量称为 字节计数所以这
this echo server we're going to keep
我们要 保持这种回声服务器
track of the number of bytes that we've
的轨道 ， 我们已经 字节数的
received from all the clients that we're
从所有 我们 的广大客户的好评
interacting with okay so there's a
用好交互 所以有
global variable called byte count which
所谓的 字节数 全局 变量
is shared by all the threads and we're
被所有 线程 共享 ，我们
going to update this this byte count
要更新这个这个字节数
variable every time we receive something
变量我们得到的东西，每次
every time we receive data from from the
每次我们 从 接收数据的时间
client and we're going to use mutex to
客户端，我们要使用互斥
protect the accesses to byte count okay
保护访问字节数好吗
so we're going to initially have to
所以我们要开始有
initialize we have to call a function
初始化我们要调用一个 函数
that initializes that initializes this
初始化初始化这个
by first initializing the mutex and then
通过首先初始化互斥 ，然后
setting byte count to zero and then
设置字节数为零，然后
within echo count itself
内回声数本身
there's some we've already seen sub
有一些 我们已经看到 子
we've already seen a way to initialize a
我们已经看到了一种方法来初始化
package you know if we have some kind of
包你知道，如果我们有某种
package of library functions that are
的库函数 是包
going to be used by multiple threads
要被 多个 线程 使用
there several ways to actually
有几种 方法 来实际
initialize this package so one way is to
初始化这个包，以便一种方法是
explicitly call have the the main thread
明确要求有主线程
call this initialization function once
调用 这个初始化函数一次
okay so we've seen that with like the S
好了，我们已经看到，随着像在S
buff package right the main thread has
BUFF包右主线程
to call the main thread calls s buffin
调用主线程调用 小号buffin
at once okay before any of the peer
之前的任何 同行 的 一次 好吗
threads executes and the worker threads
线程执行 和工作线程
executes but there's another way we can
执行，但有另一种方式，我们 可以
do this too we can have the the worker
就此别过，我们 可以有 工人
threads actually call the initialization
实际上线程调用初始化
function and we can use this technique
功能，我们可以使用这种技术
provided by by P threads where we define
通过我们定义P个线程提供
a static variable so this is a static
一个静态变量，所以这是一个静态的
local variable but you recall that this
局部变量，但你记住，这
is actually treated like a global
实际上像对待全球
variable so it every thread has access
变量，因此它的每一个线程都可以 访问
to this variable okay but but its scope
这个变量 还可以 ，但但它的范围
is limited to to the disco de cocao
仅限于迪斯科德cocao
function so no other no other function
功能所以没有其他没有其他的功能
connect can access this variable but
连接可以访问此变量 ，但
each each thread that executes this
每个执行这个每个线程
thread routine has access to it and and
线程程序都有对它的访问，并与
in this context it's treated like a
在这种情况下它是像对待
global right so if one thread updates
全球右所以如果一个线程更新
the value every other every thread sees
所有其他每个线程看到的价值
that same value okay so so we can use
相同的值 好了，所以我们可以使用
this this mechanism from P threads but
这个这个机制从 P个线程，但
so we can create this this this variable
所以我们可以 创建这个这个这个变量
of type P thread once T and initialize
P型螺纹的一次T和初始化
it to this special P threads value which
它 这个特殊的P个线程值
is sort of like the P threads
有点像在P线
uninitialized value so this is a value
未初始化的值，因此这是一个值
that P threads knows about that
即P个线程知道有关
indicates that that this variable wants
表明这个 变量要
hasn't done
没有做过
initialized and then and then we call
初始化，然后，然后我们称之为
the pthread once function passing at
在并行线程一次函数在传递
this this variable that we the address
这个这个变量， 我们的地址
of this variable created that we created
这个变量来创建我们创建
and the address of the function to call
和函数的地址调用
to initialize whatever it is we want to
初始化不管它是什么 ， 我们 要
initialize in this case the echo count
初始化在这种情况下， 回声计数
the the echo count variable and so what
该回声计数 变量还等什么
this does every thread will call P
但这每一个线程将调用 P
thread once but only one thread will
线程一次，但只有一个线程会
actually call the the initialization
实际调用初始化
function only the very first thread that
功能 中 ， 只有 第一个线程
executes speech read once will will call
执行话音读一次都会 将调用
it the other threads this this P thread
它的其他线程这这名P线程
wants call will be like a no op yes
希望呼叫就会像无操作 是
question well that's the other option so
问题嗯，这是其他选项，
so the advantage of this is that you can
所以这样做的好处是，你可以
you I guess the advantage is I I don't
你我猜的优点是II不
know that it's just another way you can
知道这只是另一种 方式，你可以
do it you I guess it avoids it avoids
做到这一点，你我猜它避免它避免了
having to do it in the master thread
不得不这样做在主线程
that you can you can make your you can
你可以，你可以 让你的你可以
make this package sort of self-contained
使这个包排序自足
right that you're not you're not really
对的，你不是你不是真的
counting on the master doing anything
在主做任何计数
but yeah that's that's the other way we
但是， 是的这是这是另一种方式，我们
could have done it so I just wanted to
可以做，所以我只是想
show you this this this other technique
告诉你这这这等技术
okay so once we once we initialize once
好了，所以一旦我们，一旦我们初始化一次
we once some thread calls an ED echo
我们一旦某个线程调用一个ED回声
count then we initialize the reo package
算上那么我们初始化REO包
for all of our accesses on this
我们 所有 的访问对这个
connected descriptor and then we
连接描述符，然后我们
repeatedly read a line of text from the
反复从所读的文本行
client okay and then in
客户端好 ，然后在
in a protected way we increment bite
在受保护的方式，我们增加 咬
count with the number of bytes that we
与字节数计算，我们
received from the client which is
从客户端是接收的
returned by this Rio read line b
这个力的读线 b返回
function and then we print a little
函数，然后我们打印了一点
message just to sort of keep track so we
消息只是为了某种跟踪 ，所以我们
can see keep track of our running total
可以看到保持我们的运行总的轨道
and then we release the mutex on this on
然后我们释放这个互斥
the byte count the global byte count
字节计数全球字节数
variable and then we echo that line back
变量，然后我们回显回线
to the client
到客户端
okay so any questions about that
好了，所以有关的任何问题
yes question the line cleared it to do
是的，这个行清除它做
first connect okay the question is the
先连接好这个问题 是
line that declares the static variable
在线声明静态变量
once will it only be executed the first
一旦将只执行 第一
time a thread executes that statement no
时间一个线程执行 没有这种说法
it's so the answer is no every every
它是如此的答案是否定的每家每户
thread will define this variable and
线程将定义这个变量和
assign it this to this this this P
它这个分配给这个本该p
thread wants value okay what will only
线程要值 好东西只会
happen once is the call to a net echo
发生一次是调用的净回声
count okay so the first thread that
算好了，所以第一个线程
executes this P thread once call will
执行所该p线程调用一次会
actually call an ED echo count every
其实叫ED回声计数每
other thread every subsequent thread
其他线程以后每线程
will not call it I'll be like a no op
会不会把它我会像无操作
yeah uses the ones it's just an opaque
是的使用它只是 一个不透明的那些
the declaration won't be be setting the
该声明将不被设置
flag everything is because often it yeah
旗一切都是因为经常是啊
somehow it will but somehow the peachoid
不知它会，但不知该 peachoid
wants is keeping track that it's it's
想要的是跟踪，这是它的
executed okay so I I'm really not sure
还好执行，所以我，我真的不知道
how how its implemented okay so somehow
如何如何 好 它的实现 ，从而以某种方式
pthread wants yeah I guess every you
并行线程想是的，我猜你每次
know this I mean this is just the C
知道我的意思是 ，这仅仅是C ^
declaration right so there's no the P
报关权，所以没有在P
threads has no control over declarations
线程拥有的声明没有控制
right so every thread will get it every
权利，使每个线程会得到它的每一个
thread will sort of update this static
线程将排序更新此静
variable and you're right if the first
可变的，你是对的，如果第一
thread the second thread would would
线程第二个线程会 会
overwrite this value again but somehow
再次，但不知何故覆盖该值
Pete's read once can keeps track of that
皮特的读取一次可以 保持跟踪
okay in a in some way that I I'm not
还好在以某种方式 说我我不
sure about how that works but this is
肯定是如何工作的，但是这 是
this is the way you get that behavior
这就是你得到的是行为方式
in others there's some other issues
在别人有一些其他的问题
around synchronizing threads sort of
各地同步排序的线程
correctness issues that we have to be
我们必须正确性问题
aware of and so I hope you I hope you're
知道的，所以我希望你，我希望你
sort of getting the sense that the
排序得到这个 意义上 ，
threaded programming is is kind of a
线程编程是怎么样的
tricky business right and so one issue
棘手的业务权等的一个问题
that we always have to be aware of is is
我们 始终必须 了解的是被
is this idea called thread safety so in
被称为这个想法线程安全所以在
general a thread routine can only should
一般一个线程程序 只能应
only call functions that are that are
只有通话功能是是
thread safe that have this property
具有此特性线程安全
called thread safety okay and a function
所谓的线程安全 好和功能
is thread safe it's and only if that
是线程安全的它是且仅当
function can be invoked by multiple
功能可以 由 多个 被 调用
threads at the same time okay so if we
与此同时线程好了，所以如果我们
have a function f its thread safe if and
有一个函数f 它的线程安全的，如果和
only if its execution can be interleaved
只有当它的执行可以交叉
by multiple threads okay
多线程好吗
and so we can identify a four different
所以我们可以找出四个不同
classes of thread unsafe functions so
线程不安全的功能 ，使类
one class is the functions that failed
一类是失败的功能
to protect shared variables with mutexes
保护与互斥的共享变量
okay so we've already seen that with bad
好了，我们已经看到，随着坏
count that was an example of a threat
算上这是一个 威胁 的例子
unsafe that main routine was an example
不安全该主程序是一个例子
of an unsafe thread function now the
现在不安全线程函数
thread function was an example of an
线程函数是的一个例子
unsafe thread function because it didn't
不安全的线程功能，因为它没有
protect the act of the update of the
保护 的 更新行为
count variable another class of
算上可变另一类
functions that that our thread unsafe is
函数， 我们的 主题是不安全
are those functions that keep track of
是那些 保持跟踪功能
State across multiple indications so if
在多个国家 的指示，所以如果
they're storing State in some global
他们存储状态的一些全局
global variable private or public global
全局变量的私人或公共全球
variable the net that's thread unsafe
这就是线程不安全的变量的净
because multiple threads will be
因为多个线程会
accessing that state another way another
访问该 状态的 其他方式的另一
kind of thread unsafe function or
一种线程不安全的功能或
functions that return a pointer to a
返回一个指向功能
static variable so there's there's
静态变量所以有有
there's a number of functions in the
有一个在多项功能
standard c library that were written
写的是标准C库
before threads or even on anybody's
线程之前甚至对任何人的
radar and so so an example is the C time
雷达等这样的例子是 C时间
function which takes as an argument a
函数，它接受作为自变量的
time struck two binary time struct and
时间击中两个二元结构的时间和
returns a pointer to a string date and
返回一个字符串指针的日期和
time string but the address in that
时间字符串，但在 该地址
pointer is always the same right so the
指针总是相同的权利，因此
this function is defining some kind of
此功能是定义某种
static variable and it's always returned
静态变量，它总是返回
and then it's it it's converting the
然后就是它它的转换
binary time struct into into a string
二元结构的时间进入到一个字符串
that's always at the same location and
这总是在相同的位置和
it's returning the address of that
它返回的该地址
string so every invocation returns the
字符串，每次调用返回
exact same address but with different
确切地址相同，但不同的
content at that address okay and this
在该地址 的内容 很好，而且这
you know they just they didn't realize
你知道他们 只是 他们没有意识到
that this was a bad thing to do for
这是 一个坏事 做
threaded programs because nobody was
线程程序，因为没有人
writing threaded programs at the time
在一次写线程程序
and then obviously any function that
然后显然任何功能
calls and unthread unsafe function is
电话和卸不安全功能
threat unsafe okay so let's look at
威胁不安全好了，让我们来看看
these these different classes of
这些这些不同 类别的
functions okay so the class one
功能 好了，所以 一个 类
functions failed to protect shared
功能无法保护共享
variables and so the fix as we've seen
变量等修复，因为我们已经看到
is to use T and V to guarantee mutually
是使用T和V，以保证相互
exclusive access and thereby protect the
独占访问，从而保护了
accesses to the variable so we saw this
访问变量，所以我们看到这个
with that good count program and then
与良好的计数程序 ，然后
the the problem is and also as we saw
的问题，也 正如我们所看到
with good count is that the
具有良好的计数是，
synchronization operations can be slow
同步操作可以是慢
so if they're in a tight inner loop it
所以，如果他们在 紧张的内环它
can it can really slow your program down
可它确实能降低运行速度
okay the class 2 thread on safe
还好在安全类2线
functions rely on some kind of
功能依赖于某种
persistent state across invocations of
跨越调用持久化状态
that function ok so the classic example
该函数确定 ，所以经典的例子
is the Lipsy rand function whose and
是Lipsy兰特函数，其与
this the and implementation of which is
这一点和实施该计划是
I took from the K in our book so this
我从K个参加了我们的书所以这
this R and this is a pseudo
该R，这是一个伪
pseudo-random number generator a pseudo
伪随机数生成器的伪
random in the sense that if you give it
随机在这个意义上，如果 你给它
the same key it will return the same
相同的密钥将返回 相同的
sequence of values ok so this is kind of
值的 顺序 确定，所以这 是一种
nice because it allows when you're
不错，因为 它允许当你
testing it allows repeatability so every
测试它允许重复性 所以每
time you call it if you call it with the
一次调用它，如果你用它打电话
same seed you can you're guaranteed
你可以你保证相同的种子
you'll get the same result and the way
你会得到相同的结果和方式
this is implemented is that there's at
这 实现 的是，有在这
the seed if there's there's a seed
如果有有种子的种子
variable called next which is used in
可变称为下这是在使用
each iteration of the random number
随机数的每次迭代
generator and it's it's defined as a
发电机和它的它定义为一个
global private so static makes it
全球私人因此静态使它
private so it's not accessible to
私人所以它不是访问
programs that are calling the rand
被调用程序兰特
function but it's it's used by the rand
功能，但它的它的使用兰德
function and so this variable is
功能，因此该变量 是
initialized to 1 there's a function
初始化为1有一个功能
called s Rand which allows the user to
称为S兰德，其允许用户 给
set the seed value so that
设置种子值， 使得
the default speed value is one but if
默认速度值是 一个 ，但如果
the user calls s ran they can pass in a
用户来电小号 跑，他们可以在一传
seed which will be then which will be
种子，将其然后将
which is just assigned to this this next
这是刚刚分配到这个这下
variable and then each iteration of Rand
变量，然后每个 兰德 的 迭代
does an operation on the seed so it
确实在种子上，以便它的操作
takes that the next value that's going
采用，未来值 是怎么回事
to be used is the is a property of the
所使用的是是 的 一个属性
previous value the function of the
前值 的 功能
previous value and then it returns a
以前的 值，然后返回一个
pseudo-random number that's a function
伪随机数，这是一个功能
of that next value okay so it's relying
没关系，明年价值的，所以它依赖
on this each iteration each time you
在每次这样每次迭代
call Rand you're relying on the this
叫兰德你依靠这
next value that was computed by the
下，是由所计算的值
previous time that you call three and
以前的时候，你叫三
okay now this is perfectly fine and
现在没事了，这 是完全正常的 ，并
there's no problem with this in a
有没有问题 ，这在
non-threaded situation but what happens
非螺纹的情况，但会发生什么
it's multiple threads now so suppose you
它的多线程现在这样想你
have multiple threads and and they're
有多个线程，和他们
each calling this rand function sort of
每个调用这个函数兰特的排序
interleaving calls to two Rand okay be
交错调用两个兰德还好是
the fact that that Rand is relying on
这样的事实： 兰德公司依托
this previous state if multiple threads
这个以前的状态，如果多个线程
are calling Rand it's going to break the
呼吁兰德这将打破
pseudo-random property so each thread
伪随机属性，因此每个线程
that the the random numbers that each
该随机数，每
thread gets back are not only a function
螺纹回来不仅是一个功能
of the previous the seed from the
从先前的种子的
previous time that thread called the
以前的时候，线程调用
function but also also a function of the
功能也同样的功能
other threads that are calling it right
其他线程呼吁 是 正确的
so so if a particular thread calls this
所以所以，如果一个特定的线程 调用此
random number generator multiple times
随机数发生器多次
it potentially won't see the same
它可能不会看到相同的
sequence of pseudo-random numbers
伪随机数序列
because other threads will be jumping in
因为其他线程将被跳跃
okay and
还好 和
okay so if it's not it's not incorrect
好了，如果不是它不是不正确
and that the program will fail but if
并且，该 程序将失败，但如果
the program is counting on the
程序上的计数
pseudo-random property then it creates a
伪随机 属性 ，则它会创建一个
problem okay so the the solution to this
问题好吗 所以 ，要解决这个
is to rewrite Rand and require it to
被改写 兰德并要求它
require the caller to keep track of this
需要调用者跟踪这个
next variable okay so each caller will
下一个变量好了，所以每个来电者将
keep its own local copy of next and it
保持自己的本地副本， 下一个 和 它
will pass in a pointer to R and R and
将指针 传递 给 R和R与
we'll compute that value so now this
我们将计算该值，因此现在这个
will be updating state in the calling
在调用 将更新 状态
the calling thread but this is local
调用 线程，但这是局部的
state on the on that thread stack okay
状态的线程堆栈好吗
so every thread will have its own copy
所以每个线程都有自己的副本
of of next so we but we have to create a
明年，所以 我们，但我们必须创建一个
new function and what we'll call it
新的功能，我们叫它
underscore R the stands for reentrant
下划线的R代表折返
which is a property we'll look at in
这是一个属性，我们将看看
just a second but it's more work for the
只是第二，但它的更多的工作
programmer because now the programmer
程序员因为现在的程序员
has to maintain this this sort of this
必须 保持这种这种这种
next value okay
下一个值好吗
okay another way that threads that
还好另一种方式线程
functions are unsafe is this this is are
功能是不安全的就是这个，这是有
these functions that always retain a
这些功能 总是保留
return a pointer to some global to the
返回一个指向一些全球性的
same global variable or typically it's a
同一个全局变量或通常这是一个
static variable but they always return
静态变量，但他们总是返回
the same value each time the same
每次相同 的值相同
address okay so you can see this is
解决好了，所以你可以看到这是
similar to that race that we encountered
类似于我们遇到的那场比赛
before where we're passing the address
这里我们 传递的 地址之前
of a connected file descriptor to a
连接的文件描述符到的
worker thread okay so now we're creating
工作线程好了，所以现在我们正在 创建
a race so let's say one thread let's say
一场比赛让我们说一个线程假设
one thread calls this function so for
一个线程调用这个 函数 所以 对于
example C time takes this this time
实施例 C时间借此这个时间
struct as an argument okay which can
结构作为 行 参数 其可以
correspond to an arbitrary time it could
对应于它可以任意时间
be the current time or just some
是当前时间或只是 一些
arbitrary time that the caller
任意时间， 来电者
constructed and it returns a pointer to
构造和它返回一个指向
a charge star so it just returns a
一个当家球星所以 它只是 返回
pointer to a string that represents the
指针表示该字符串
date and the time its own ASCII ASCII
日期和时间的自己的ASCII ASCII
string that that represents the date and
字符串， 表示日期和
time but it's always it's always
时间，但它总是 它总是
returning a pointer to the same the same
返回指针到相同的同一
location in memory okay so you can see
在存储位置好，所以你可以看到
the problem if thread a calls the C time
如果一个线程调用 C时间 问题
function with one with one time struck
功能与一个有一个时间来袭
it gets back a pointer to the to the
它回来的指针到
character string corresponding to that
对应于 字符串
time struct but now let's say before the
时间结构，但现在我们之前说
four thread a can use that read that
核四线程一个可以使用阅读
that string another thread call C time
该字符串另一个线程调用 C时间
and that instance of C time will
和C时间该实例会
overwrite that the copy of the time
覆盖该时间的复制
string for that that thread a is
字符串对于该线程是
computed so when thread a finally gets a
计算所以，当线程最终得到一个
chance to access that time string its
机会访问时间字符串的
accessing thread B's time string and not
访问线程B的时间字符串，而不是
three days time string
三天的时间串
okay and it just depends if thread a can
还好，它只是取决于如果线程一罐
get to that and read that variable
到达那个和读取变量
before thread B over writes it then
前线程B在写它，然后
everything's fine otherwise thread a is
一切都 很好，否则线程是一个
accessing the wrong time string okay so
访问了错误的时间串 好了，
there's there's a couple of ways to fix
还有的有一对夫妇的方式来解决
this like we could rewrite the the
这就像我们可以重写 的
function the C time function to take as
函数C时间函数采取如
add another argument that passes in the
添加一个通过了另一种说法
the location the address of the time
位置的时间地址
string so we could require that the
串，所以我们可以要求该
caller to allocate space for the time
主叫方的时间分配空间
string and passing the address to the C
串并传递地址到C
time function okay but this has this
时间功能不错，但这个有这
says this would require us to change all
说， 这需要我们改变一切
the instances where we call C time but
在这里我们调用C时的情况，但
we'd also have to change the
我们也不得不改变
implementation of C time in the live in
实施 C时间在直播中
the Lipsy in the library right and so we
在Lipsy 库中的权利，所以我们
can't we don't have access to Lib C
我们不能没有 访问库ç
source on our system right so that
来源我们的系统上的权利 ， 使
that's just not a feasible thing plus it
这只是不是一个可行的 事情 ，再加上它
would break every other program that
将打破所有其他程序
called C time right so we just can't do
所谓的C正确的时间，所以我们只是不能做
that
那
the another of a better option is to
另一个更好的选择的是
create a new function of our own okay
创建我们自己的新功能好吗
called C time underscore TTS for thread
所谓的C时强调TTS线程
safe so we'll create our own sort of
安全，所以我们将创建我们 自己 的 那种
wrapper function for the C time and
为C时包装函数和
we'll use a technique called lock and
我们将使用一种叫做锁
copy to to provide thread safe access to
复制到提供线程安全的访问
2c time so the way it works is it will
2C时间，所以 它 的 工作方式 是它会
write this new function C time
写这个新的函数C时间
underscore TS which just like c time
下划线TS 刚刚如c时间
takes this a pointer to this time struct
这需要一个指向这次结构
but then it adds the second argument
但随后增加了第二个参数
which is a pointer to the threat of
这是一个指向的威胁
threads private copy of the time string
线程的时间字符串的私有副本
okay so the caller allocates the space
好了 ，所以调用者分配的空间
and passes the pointer to this to that
并传递指向此该
to that string
该字符串
and then within si time we have a local
然后SI的时间内，我们有一个地方
variable called shared the shared
可变称为共享 的共享
pointer okay so this is going to point
指针好了，这是怎么回事点
to that that that shared global data
到这是全球共享数据
structure that C time is is accessing
结构C时间是正在访问
and so first we do the lock
所以首先我们要做的锁
that's the lock part of lock and copy by
这是由锁和复制的锁定部分
acquiring a mutex and then we call C
获取互斥 ，然后我们调用C
time so only one thread at a time we'll
时间在时间 ，所以只有一个线程，我们将
have this mutex
有这种互斥
so whatever thread so once once we
因此无论线程，这样一次一次我们
return from T we know that we're the
从T回流，我们知道我们 的
only thread in this in this critical
只有在这个线程在这个关键
section so we call C time the normal lit
部分 因此，我们调用C时正常 点亮
CC time function which returns a pointer
它返回一个指针CC时间函数
to this to the same location and then we
这个相同的位置，然后我们
do the copy part we copy that that
做文案的一部分，我们复制的是
string to the private string that was
字符串私人字符串是
passed in just into our function once
在刚刚进入我们的函数传递一次
we've done the copy then we can release
我们已经做了拷贝，然后我们就可以释放
the new text and then we return a
新的文本，然后我们返回
pointer we return private P back to the
指针我们回到私人P 回
caller okay so and we don't we don't
来电者好了，所以，我们不我们不
this is just more of a convenience to
这仅仅是一个更方便的来
the caller
呼叫者
because programs that are using C time
因为使用的是C时段节目
are expecting to get that pointer back
期待得到该指针回
okay so by using lock and copy we have
好了，通过使用锁和复制，我们有
to we have to make changes we have to
到我们必须做出 我们必须改变
write this new function but it's fairly
写这个新的功能，但它是相当
simple and then we have to make changes
简单， 那么我们就必须做出改变
every place in our program where we call
在我们的程序中的每个地方， 我们称之为
C time we have to update those two calls
C时间，我们必须更新这 两个电话
to see time underscore TS and create
看一次强调TS和创造
this create this local string array okay
这个创建这个本地字符串数组好吗
yes
是
why-why-why time like the variables out
为什么，为什么，为什么时间像变量出来
of consciousness
意识
right
对
well typically these functions are
井通常这些功能是
returning pointers to some data
返回指向一些数据
structure and so they're they're sort of
结构等 他们有 几分
updating the data structure and then
更新数据结构， 然后
returning a pointer to it so it wouldn't
返回一个指向它，所以它不会
make I don't know how I guess it could
让我不知道我是怎么想这可能
return it struct and would always return
返回其 结构，并会始终返回
now now I can't think of any I can't
现在我现在想不出任何我不能
think of any reason why they would
想不出什么原因，他们会
return anything but a pointer because
返回任何东西 ，但因为指针
they're they're typically updating some
他们他们 通常更新一些
some data structure and then returning a
一些数据结构，然后返回
pointer to it
指针指向它
if they were returning if they were
如果他们回来，如果他们
returning scalars those scalars would
返回标量的标量会
always be returned in EAX or RA X all
总是在EAX 或 RA X全部返还
right so actually that would be okay all
右所以 实际上 这将是 所有好
right it would just be it's the pointer
正确的那只是它的指针
that causes the problem because it's
引起 该 问题，因为它是
always returning that value in EI x but
总是返回在 EI X 中的价值 ，但
it's always returning the same value in
它总是在返回的值相同
EAX always pointing to the same the same
EAX总是指向 相同的同
data structure okay good
数据结构一般好
okay now one dub one potentially
现在没事了一个配音一个潜在的
significant disadvantage of lock and
锁显著的缺点和
copy is that this this copy might not
副本是这个这个副本可能不
always be as simple as just doing like a
始终为 只是做像 那样简单
stir copy if if it's a complex DIF if
搅拌副本，如果，如果它是一个复杂的 ，如果DIF
the function that you're calling is
你正在调用该函数
computing some complex data structure
计算一些复杂的数据结构
like a nested you know a struct which
像一个嵌套你知道一个结构，其
contain structs and pointers to arrays
包含结构和指向数组的指针
then this copy can get can get quite
那么这个副本可以得到可以得到相当
complicated right it would require what
它需要什么复杂的权
we call a deep copy so that can be that
我们所说的深拷贝，这样可以 是
can be very difficult to but in this
可能是非常困难 的，但在这
case it's simple we're just we're just
情况下，它很简单，我们只是我们只是
doing a we're just copying one string to
做我们只是复制一个字符串
another okay and then finally the the
另一个好，然后 最后的
fourth class of thread unsafe functions
第四 类的螺纹不安全的函数
are functions that call unsafe functions
是 不安全的 调用 函数的函数
right so it's kind of obvious and then
右所以它是一种明显的，然后
the obvious fix is to not call thread
显而易见的解决方法是不调用线程
unsafe functions from within your
从内部不安全的功能
function and then you can make it thread
功能，然后你可以把它 线程
safe now there's a very interesting an
安全现在有一个 非常有趣的
important subclass of thread safe
线程安全的重要子类
functions called reentered functions so
函数调用重新输入功能，使
a reentrant a function is reentrant if
一个可重入函数可重入，如果
it contains no accesses to shared to
它不包含访问共享
shared variables okay so if all the if
共享变量好了，所以如果要是所有
every variable that it accesses is
每次它访问变量是
contained on the is declared as a local
包含在被声明为本地
variable and stored on the stack for
可变的 ，并且存储在栈上
that function okay that's called a
该功能还行这就是所谓的一
reentrant function and because there's
折返功能，因为有
no accesses of any kind to shared
没有访问任何类型的共享
variables there's no there's no
变量有没有没有
synchronization required because every
由于需要在每次同步
function is operating accessing its own
功能运行时访问自己的
local copy of all the variables and it's
所有的变量和它的本地副本
multiple threads execute two instances
多线程执行两个实例
of a reentrant function it's okay each
一个可重入函数 的 也没关系各
thread has its own separate stack so you
线程都有自己独立的堆栈，所以你
don't need to worry about any kind of
不必担心任何种类的
synchronization they can run
他们可以运行同步
independently so the reason we entering
所以独立的原因 ，我们进入
functions are so important is because
功能是如此重要，是因为
it's expensive to do
它的价格昂贵做
synchronization and so what you can
同步还等什么，你 可以
avoid it completely with these reaction
与这些反应完全避免它
function reentrant functions so that
功能折返 功能， 使
they're efficient so is that as the
他们是如此高效的是，作为
diagram shows every reentrant function
图显示每一重入函数
is thread safe but not every thread safe
是线程安全的，但不是每一个线程安全
function is reentrant so we saw that
功能折返，所以我们看到，
before right when we have a function
权利之前 ，当我们有一个函数
that accesses a shared variable we can
访问共享变量，我们 可以
make it thread safe by protecting it
使其通过保护线程安全
with a mutex okay but it's not real
用互斥锁还可以，但它不是 真正的
trend because it's actually it's
趋势，因为它实际上是
accessing shared variables okay now on
访问共享变量的 还好现在开始
all the functions in the standard c
在标准C的所有功能
library which are enumerated in the back
这是在后面列举库
of your k and r texture thread safe okay
你的K 和 R 质感线程安全的好
but not not necessarily reentrant and
但不一定重返进入
most most this calls our thread safe
最最最这就要求我们的线程安全
with just a with a few exceptions that
只需有几个例外
I've listed here I don't I don't think I
我在这里列出我不，我不认为我
don't think this is complete but these
不要以为这是完整的，但这些
are just examples of some notable ones
只是一些显着的人的例子
and so for each each of these thread
所以每一个每一个 线程
unsafe functions Linux provides a
不安全的函数Linux提供了一个
reentrant version which is denoted by
这是由表示重入版本
underscore R and then that reentrant
下划线R和然后该折返
version has a different different set of
版本有不同的组不同的
parameters typically the only exception
参数通常是 唯一 的 例外
that I know about is I net n to a which
我知道是我净n到这
is an episode of an obsolete Network
是一个 过时的 网络 的一个插曲
protocol for converting sort of binary
协议转换排序二进制的
Network addresses to human readable
网络地址 ，以人类可读
ASCII addresses but this is this is
ASCII地址，但是这是，这是
often not deleted by by other calls so
往往不是由其他 的电话，以 通过删除
it's I guess they just never never
这是我想他们只是从来就不曾
bothered to create a reentrant version
不屑于创建一个重入版本
for it because there's there's other
它因为有有其他
options alternatives to using that
选项替代使用
okay another so another thing we have to
还好另一个让 我们不得不 另一 件事
worry about is we've seen is races again
担心的是，我们已经看到又是种族
this is the real Bugaboo in in threaded
这是在螺纹真正布盖布
programs and it typically involves some
程序，它通常涉及到一些
kind of unexpected sharing so in this
一种意想不到的共享，以便在这
case we're revisit this this this
情况下，我们重温这这这
incorrect threaded program that where we
不正确线程程序，在那里我们
introduce introduced arrays by passing
引入 通过使 引入的阵列
when we create the thread we we pass the
当我们创建线程，我们我们通过
argument to the thread which is like the
参数线程这就 好比
local thread ID we pass an address of a
本地线程ID 我们传递的一个地址
variable that we have stored on the
我们已经存储在变量
stack and it's getting the I that the
栈和它 得到 我的
the loop iterator and so we've seen that
将循环迭代，所以我们已经看到，
this causes this causes array so we in
这会导致这会导致数组 ， 所以 我们在
quickly we set initially is 0 then we
很快我们最初设置 为0，那么我们
create a new thread which is pure thread
创建一个新的线程是纯线
0 and then this thread dereferences the
0，则该线程取消引用
pointer to get its local copy of the
指针以获得其本地的副本
this sort of local thread ID but now
这种局部线程ID，但现在的
we've introduced the race between the
我们已经推出了之间的竞争
increment of I and the dereferencing of
我和增量的间接引用
the incrementing of I and the main
我和 主递增
thread and the dereferencing of I in the
螺纹和我在反引用
peer thread so if this dereferencing
对线程因此，如果这个反引用
happens before I is incremented than
发生了，我比以前增加
we're good but if this dereferencing
我们是很好的，但如果这个提领
happens after we increment I so in other
碰巧我们在其他增加我打完
words that when I equal 1 then we get
也就是说，当我等于1，则我们得到
the wrong value in the peer thread for
在同行线程错误的值
for my ID
我的ID
so you might wonder I think there was a
所以你可能会问，我觉得有一个
question before about you know this
你 知道这个问题之前，
seems that the odds of this happening
看来这种情况发生 的几率
seems so low why why are you even
似乎如此之低，为什么，为什么你 连
worrying about it so we actually create
担心，所以我们实际上创建
just to sort of test this out we wrote a
只是排序测试了这一点，我们写了一个
program to see if we could see if we
程序，看看 我们可以看到，如果 我们
could actually could see this race in
其实可以看得出这场比赛中
practice and that's why the great things
练习，这就是为什么伟大的事情
about like 2:13 is that you can just try
约2:13一样的是， 你 可以试试
stuff out right so so we just tried it
东西出来 的权利 等等，所以我们 刚刚试了一下
out so we wrote it we wrote a simple
出来，所以我们写了它，我们写了一个简单的
main thread that creates a hundred
创建一百个主线程
different threads each with and we
每个和我们不同的线程
passed the art as the argument we task
通过艺术的说法，我们的任务
the address of of this local variable I
这个局部变量 我 的地址
okay and then in each peer thread we
好吧，然后在每个对等线程我们
detach the thread dereference and then
分离线程提领，然后
we have a function that saves the value
我们有保存价值的功能
so where we're storing we're storing
所以，我们要存储 我们存储
that value of I for future reference
我以供将来参考该值
okay so now if there's no race each of
还好 所以现在如果没有你追我赶 的
the 100 threads would get a separate
在100个线程会得到一个独立的
distinct thread ID right so each each
不同线程ID右所以每个各
value 0 through 99 if we made a
值0到99，如果我们做了一个
histogram of it there would be exactly
它的柱状图会有完全相同
one instance of each of each value of I
每一个我每个值的一个实例
ok but if there was a race there would
确定 ，但如果有一场比赛将有
be for some values of I there would be
是的我的一些值 会有
multiple instances that were encountered
中遇到的多个实例
in multiple threads ok so you can see if
在多线程确定，所以你可以看到，如果
we go back here if if if we lose if the
我们再回到这里如果，如果，如果我们输了，如果
peer thread loses the race and I gets
对线程失去了比赛，我得到
incremented before it can dereference
之后才能提领递增
now we've got peer thread 0 actually
现在我们已经有了对线程 0实际上
gets a an ID of 1 ok
得到 一个1个 OK 的ID
and then Pierre thread one if there's no
然后皮埃尔线 之一，如果没有
race it'll-it'll get the correct value
比赛稍后即，稍后即得到正确的值
of one so now we've got two instances of
一所以现在我们有两个实例
one okay so let's look so this is the
一个好 了，让我们来看看，所以这是的
case so we've plotted the results for a
这样的情况下，我们已经绘制的结果
case where there's no race so along the
情况下不会产生竞争，从而沿
x-axis sorry this is too small the
x轴抱歉，这是太小的
x-axis gives us all the 100 values of I
x轴为我们提供了所有 的 我 的100个 值
0 through 99 and then the y-axis is the
0至99，然后 将y轴是
count so this is a hit we're doing a
算上所以这是我们正在做一个一击
histogram of for these all the values 0
对这些所有值0直方图
through 99 so in this case every value
通过99所以在这种情况下，每个值
has exactly one instance so no race
有且只有一个实例，这样没有竞争
there was no race in no races involved
有在不涉及种族没有种族
in all 99 are all 100 instances who run
在所有99是 谁运行 的所有100个 实例
it on a single core laptop so now each
它在单核笔记本电脑 所以现在每
thread is sort of taking its turn on a
线程排序的 同时反过来对
single core it happens a few times right
单芯它发生了几次权
so there's a few times where the one
所以有几次， 其中 一个
thread gets preempted and the other
线程被抢占，而另一
thread begins to run before it can so
线程开始 运行之前， 它可以 使
the peers 1 1 thread gets preempted
同行11个线程被抢占
before I can dereference the variable so
之前，我可以取消引用变量，以便
it gets the wrong the wrong value but
它得到了错误的错误值，但
it's not very common it just it happened
这不是很常见，它只是它发生
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 times but now if we run
1 2 3 4 5 6 7倍 ，但现在如果我们运行
this program on a on a multi-core server
这个程序在多核服务器上
you can see it happens a lot in fact it
你可以看到它发生了很多 实际上它
happens most of the time so it almost
发生的大部分时间，因此几乎
never we almost never get the correct
我们从未几乎从来没有得到正确的
the correct value for for my ID
对于我的ID正确的值
okay so this is just another example of
好了，这是 又一个例子
some of the create the things I can just
一些创造的 东西我可以
drive you crazy if you're not careful
推动你疯了，如果你 不小心
when you when you program is and threads
当您在程序和线程
with threads okay and as so as we saw
用好线程和使我们看到了
the way to eliminate these kind of
消除 这些种 方式
erases is to avoid this the sharing of
擦除是为了避免这种共享
state and in this case by allocating for
状态， 在 这种情况下，通过对分配
each thread allocating a separate block
每个线程分配一个单独的块
in the in the heat that will hold the
在中热量将举行
that will hold the the local ID for that
将持有的 本地 ID
thread and then passing a pointer to
线程，然后指针传递到
that that unique block of storage to the
该 存储到该唯一的块
thread
线
okay so if that if all of that isn't
好了，如果，如果所有的，是不是
enough to worry about and by now you
足够的理由担心而现在你
should be losing sleep at the very
应在非常失去的睡眠
thought of writing a threaded program
想到写一个线程程序
another thing to worry about is deadlock
另一件事要担心的是僵局
okay so here a program is deadlocked if
好了，所以这里的程序，如果僵持
it's waiting for some condition to occur
它在等待出现一些状况
that will never occur okay so let's say
这不会发生好了，让我们说
a typical scenario right T P is the
一个典型的场景右 TP是
potential the P operation is a potential
电势的P动作是一个潜在的
problem because it blocks right and it's
问题，因为它会 阻止正确的，它的
waiting for that semaphore that it's
等待的信号， 它的
blocking on to become nonzero well it's
阻塞成为非零那么它的
it's not too hard to imagine scenarios
这不是太难以想象的场景
where some there's some combination of
其中一些有一些组合
P's of P operations that sort of block
P公司 P 的 操作那种块
each other out okay and make it
对方出好，并使其
impossible for the condition they're
不可能他们的条件
waiting on to occur so for example let's
等待上发生这样的 例子，让我们
say you've got two two threads that need
说你有两个两个线程需要
two two threads one and two that need
二两线一和二需要
two different resources a and B in order
两个不同的资源A和B 顺序
to proceed so they have to acquire they
继续让他们必须获得他们
have to do a PE on the mutex that on the
要做互斥一个PE，关于
mutex that that's associated with the
互斥锁是与关联
new Texas that are associated with these
与这些 相关的新德州
two resources so let's say process one
两种资源让我们说一个过程
acquires a so it does a P on phase mutex
取得它确实是这样的阶段互斥为P
that's one it's okay so it succeeds that
这是一个它的好了，所以它成功 的是
it so it acquires that resource and then
它，所以它获得该资源，然后
it gets preempted by thread to which
它被通过线程抢占到
acquires B first instead of acquiring a
获取B首先， 而不是获取
thread B for some reason acquires B so
由于某种原因，线程B获得B上
now thread a holds the lock on resource
现在线程持有资源的锁
a and thread two holds the lock on
和线程两项诉讼上的锁
resource B and so now let's say process
资源B，因此现在让我们说过程
thread two gets preempted so now and
线程目前两人被抢占左右，
thread one runs and so now it's waiting
一个线程运行，因此现在它的 等待
it's trying to do two tries to acquire
它试图做两次尝试收购
the the lock on resource b-but threat to
在资源B，但威胁到锁
our whole deadlock and at the same time
我们整个的僵局，并在同一时间
thread to tries to acquire the lock on
线程试图获取 的锁
resource a but process one is holding
资源，但过程中的一个持有
that right so they're each so here's the
这一权利使 他们每个所以这里的
case where thread a is waiting for this
其中一个线程 在等待这种情况下，
semaphore associated with B to become
信号量与B相关联，成为
non zero so it's blocked in this P
非零所以它挡在这名 P
operation and at the same time thread
操作并在同一时间线
two is blocked in the P operation for
2被阻止在用于P操作
for for resource a neither of those
对于资源既不是那些
semaphores will ever be released so
信号灯将永远被释放，
thread one and two are deadlocked okay
线程一和二僵持好吗
and it it happened because just there
而且它的发生是因为就在那里
was this innocuous little bug in this
这是无害的小虫子 在这
case where one the threads acquired
其中一个线程获取的情况下
their resources in different orders
他们以不同的顺序资源
so here's an example of a program that
所以这里有一个程序的例子
deadlocks and if you looked at this you
死锁，如果你看了 这个 你
know the fact that it's wrong and buggy
知道的事实，这是错误的和马车
doesn't jump out at you right so this is
你不跳出正确的，所以这是
this kind of stuff is very subtle so
这种东西很微妙 如此
here's here's a program we're going to
这里有这里的，我们要 的 程序
create two threads we've got an array so
创建两个线程，我们已经有了一个数组 等等
and we have an array of mutexes an array
我们有互斥体 的一个数组的数组
of two mutexes so we create two threads
2个互斥的，所以我们创建了两个线程
and we pass each thread it's a local
我们 通过每一个线程是本地
thread ID so of 0 & 1 and so here we're
线程ID 所以 0和1，因此在这里我们
avoiding the race we're just casting
避免我们只是投放了比赛
this thread ID to be to a pointer okay
该线程ID是一个指针 好
which is a little strange but it's okay
这是一个有些奇怪，但也没关系
and then we're waiting for those threads
然后我们在等待 这些线程
to finish okay each thread is going to
完成好每个线程 是要
acquire to these two semaphores these
获得这 两个信号灯这些
two mutexes but it's going to do it in a
2个互斥体，但它会 做一个
different order
不同的 顺序
okay so it's going to do it as a
好了，所以它会 做它作为一个
function it's going to take the ID so
它的功能要采取的ID，这样
it's going to sew thread zero will first
这将缝制线零 将第一
acquire a mutex 0 and then and then
获得互斥0，然后再
acquire mutex 1-0 so then it will
获得互斥1-0这样的话它会
acquire mutex 1 and thread 1 will first
获得互斥体1和线程1将第一
acquire you Tech's one and then acquire
获得你技术的一个然后收购
mutex 0 okay so if we were to draw that
互斥0 好了 ，所以如果我们得出
Dyke and then and then it will attempt
戴克 ，然后，然后 它会尝试
to then it will increment count so this
到那么它会增加数量，使得此
is totally bogus but it's just to
完全是假的，但它只是
illustrate that the problem so you can
说明了 这个问题，所以 你 可以
see thread 0 does a peon semaphore 0
看到线程0做了 苦工旗语0
followed by a peon semaphore 1 and
接着是日工旗语1和
thread 1 does a peon semaphore 1
线程1做了苦工信号灯1
followed by a peon semaphore 0 and so we
接着是日工旗语0，所以我们
can see this that this is a problem very
可以看到这一点，这是一个问题 很
clearly if we go back to our progress
显然 ，如果我们回到 我们的进步
graphs
图
so if you look at thread 0 it's doing a
所以，如果你看一下线程0 这是做
peon semaphore 1 and it followed a peon
日工旗语1和它遵循一个苦工
semaphore 1 followed by a V on semaphore
旗语随后在信号量为V 1
1 and thread 1 is also is doing a peon
1和线程1也被做了苦工
1 so if you take if you take the the
1所以，如果如果你把你的取
intersection of these two regions you
这两个区域的交集你
get the forbidden region for semaphore 1
得到禁止区域的信号1
okay so this is the region that enforces
好了，所以这 是强制执行 区域
mutual exclusion so on this on this the
互斥等此此的
resource associated with semaphore 1 and
用旗语1相关的资源和
if you do the same thing for semaphore 0
如果您对旗语0做同样的事情
so here in thread 1 we're acquiring
所以在这里线程1我们收购
semaphore 0 here and releasing it here
这里信号量0，在这里将其释放
and we're in thread 0 we're acquiring it
而我们在线程0我们收购它
here and releasing it here so if you
这里和这里释放它，所以如果你
take the intersection of those two you
采取这些两路口 你
get this forbidden region for s0 ok now
现在得到S0确定该禁止区域
the problem
问题
is right is this region here this
是 对是本地区本在这里
so-called deadlock region because by the
所谓的僵局区域因为受
rules of you know time can't go
你知道规则的时间不能去
backwards art once the trajectory enters
向后艺术一旦轨迹 进入
into the this deadlock region then it's
进入这个僵局区域那么它的
doomed because there's no once it enters
注定，因为没有一次进入
this once it enters this deadlock region
这一次，它进入这个僵局区
there's nowhere for it to go eventually
有无处它去最终
no matter how it progresses every
不管它是如何进展的每
trajectory will lead to to this point
轨迹将导致这一点
here where it's boxed in and can't and
在这儿，它的盒装并不能和
can no longer proceed
不能再继续
so so and interestingly this is sort of
所以如此，有趣，这是有点
this region Dec here on the on the the
这一地区 十二月这里 就对了
sort of the tail end of the of these two
排序的这两个的尾端的
forbidden regions this represents states
禁止区域，这代表美国
that can never be reached so these are
永远不能 达到所以这些都是
unreachable states which may or may not
不可达 状态可以或可以不
be interesting and then what makes this
很有趣，那么是什么使这个
so nasty is that it's non-deterministic
所以讨厌的就是它的不确定性
right some programs some trajectories if
正确的某些程序的一些轨迹，如果
they get lucky they'll skirt this
他们很幸运，他们会绕开这个
deadlock region and then the program
死锁区域，然后程序
will run fine right there's okay so if
将会运行得很好那里也 没关系，所以如果
if its trajectory maybe just by some you
如果它的轨迹 ，也许只是一些你
know just by some arbitrary scheduling
知道只是一些随意调度
decision made by the colonel the
由上校做出决定
trajectory trajectory gets passed the
弹道轨迹被通过
deadlock region in this direction and
在这个 方向上死锁区域和
then it will eventually run without any
那么它最终将没有任何运行
problem so it's just it's only if the
问题，所以它只是它仅在
trajectory lands it within the deadlock
轨迹土地它的僵局中
region then they were that we're in
区域然后他们说我们在
trouble
麻烦
so so this is the really nasty the
所以所以这 真的是个讨厌的
really nasty part is that you may run
真是可恶的是，你可以运行
your program for a million times and
你的 一百万次 的程序 和
every trajectory every one of those
每一个轨迹的每一个
million trajectories skirts the deadlock
亿个轨迹裙子僵局
region okay but on the million and first
地区还好，但对万和第一
time that you run it it it enters the
时间，你运行它，它在进入
deadlock region and then deadlocks okay
死锁区域，然后死锁好吗
so it's it's very it's a very tough
所以这是它非常这是一个非常艰难的
problem to deal with now fortunately you
问题来 处理，现在还好你
it's easy to avoid
它很容易避免
if threads that are acquiring locks on
如果是在获取锁的线程
on resources acquire all those locks in
在资源获取所有这些锁
the same order okay so in our example if
好了，所以在我们的例子，如果以相同的顺序
we rewrite this program so that each
我们重写这个计划，使每个
thread thread 0 and thread 1 acquire
螺纹线程0和线程1获取
their locks in the same order so
他们以相同的顺序锁，使
semaphore 0 first followed by semaphore
旗语0第一后跟旗语
then if that happens and we you can see
那么，如果出现这种情况，我们可以看到
it eliminates the depth the potential
它消除 了深度的潜力
deadlock region okay so now any
死锁的区域还好所以现在任何
trajectory that we take will will be
轨迹，我们需要将将
fine because we've eliminated that that
很好，因为我们已经消除了该
that deadlock region and the the order
死锁区域和顺序
that we release the locks doesn't matter
我们释放锁不要紧
because that that sort of effects that
因为那种效应
the it affects this unreachable region
在它影响该地区无法访问
you know the size and shape of this
你知道这样做的大小和形状
unreachable reasons region but it
原因不能到达的区域，但它
there's never the order that we release
从未有我们下达订单
the locks it can never introduce a
它不可能引入锁
deadlock region okay so that's it for
死锁区好了，这就是它
today hope you all have a very nice
今天希望大家有一个非常好的
Thanksgiving holiday and we'll see you
感恩节假期 ，我们会看到你
on Tuesday
星期二